<sburb><classes>

<action class='doorTalk2' sprite='meenah' command='talk' name='Ouvrir la porte.'><args>
      @meenah_talk MEENAH: vantas donne moi ton mot de passe
      @karkat_what KARKAT: (hein ?)
      @meenah_talk MEENAH: cest ta porte nest ce pas
      @karkat_talk KARKAT: (qu’est-ce qui te fait dire ça.)
      @meenah_annoyedtalk MEENAH: le symbole sur la porte est le meme que sur ton putain de tee shirt
      @meenah_annoyedtalk:#pchooo MEENAH: allez ca va rien faire peter #pchooo
      @karkat_sullen KARKAT: (ok, ouais, c’est la mienne. peut-être que je suis juste fatigué que des sacs à merde s’introduisent dans mes souvenirs PRIVES et PERSONNELS.)
      @meenah_talk MEENAH: tu peux arreter de chuchoter ya plus personne dans le coin
      @karkat_idle KARKAT: OH
      @meenah_happytalk MEENAH: alors quel est le mot de passe
      @karkat_talk KARKAT: LAISSE-MOI PASSER, JE VAIS L'ECRIRE POUR TOI.
      @meenah_angrytalk MEENAH: allez chonchon donne le moi !!! 
      @karkat_shout KARKAT: OH MON DIEU, C’EST TELLEMENT ABSURDE. POURQUOI NE SERAIT-CE DONC PAS LA PLUS RAISONNABLE DES CHOSES AU MONDE DE JUSTE ME LAISSER TAPER MON PUTAIN DE MOT DE PASSE ???
      @meenah_fish MEENAH: mec tu veux que kankri te retrouve et te prenne encore la tete ?
      @karkat_horror:#OH-MON-DIEU KARKAT: NON !!! TOUT SAUF CA.
      @karkat_yell KARKAT: TRES BIEN, JE VAIS TE LE DONNER, JUSTE...
      @karkat_yell KARKAT: NE VA PAS L'EBRUITER.
      @karkat_talk KARKAT: LE MOT DE PASSE EST...
      @karkat_eyeroll1~dialogimg_karkat1  
      @meenah_idle:#? MEENAH: wuh
      @karkat_eyeroll2~dialogimg_karkat1 
      @meenah_wut2 MEENAH: mec parle plus fort
      @karkat_shout:#QUOI-T’ES-SOURDE KARKAT: SI JE ME HAIS AUTANT, POURQUOI JE NE ME HAINEPOUSE PAS MOI-MEME !!!!!!! 
      @meenah_wut MEENAH: cest CA ton mdp
      @meenah_annoyedtalk MEENAH: nom de lieu, quest ce que ca signifie
      @karkat_yell KARKAT: RIEN. CA NE TE REGARDE PAS.
      @karkat_sullen KARKAT: C’EST JUSTE UN TRUC QUI ME RAPPELLE UNE VIEILLE AMIE. C’EST BON ?! ON PEUT POURSUIVRE ?
      @meenah_happier MEENAH: putain ouais ! suis moi chonchon
      @meenah_creepytalk MEENAH: tu regretteras pas ma lompanie !
      @karkat_facepalm KARKAT: 
      <!-- open the door -->
</args>
<action command='removeSprite'>
	<args>thirdRoomDoor,thirdRoom</args>
	<action command='addWalkable' noDelay='true'>
		<args>thirdRoomDoorWalkable,thirdRoom</args>
		<action command='playSound' noDelay='true'>
			<args>openSound2</args>
		</action>
	</action>
</action>
</action>

   <!-- if meenah talks to karkat (while kankri is away)-->
<action class='karkatTalk2' sprite='meenah' command='talk' name='Parle à Karkat.'>
	<args>
      @meenah_idle MEENAH: (psst!)
      @meenah_happy MEENAH: (hey vantas)
      @karkat_idle KARKAT: (quoi.)
      @meenah_happytalk MEENAH: (cest ta chance)
      @meenah_creepytalk:#poisson/cassons...#he-ca-passe MEENAH: (allez poissons nous)
      @karkat_sullen KARKAT: (oh...)
      @karkat_talk KARKAT: (je ne pense pas que je sois supposé...)
      @meenah_talk MEENAH: (chonchon tu vas pas laisser ce marinerd te dicter ce que tu dois faire)
      @meenah_annoyedtalk MEENAH: (tu preferes rester ici a ecouter ses anchois disantes importanche baliriviernes toute la journee ???)
      @karkat_eyeroll1:#IMPORTANCHE-BALIRIVIERNES-?#PUTAIN-DE-TROLLS-AQUATIQUES KARKAT: (pas vraiment.)
      @meenah_creepy MEENAH: (alors VI-ENS !)
      <!-- karkat then follows -->
	</args>
	<action command='follow'>
		<args>karkat,meenah</args>
		<action command='removeAction'>
			<args>thirdRoomDoor,Open door.</args>
			<action command='removeAction'>
				<args>karkat,Talk to Karkat.</args>
				<action command='addActions'>
					<args>thirdRoomDoor,
						<action class='doorTalk2'/>
					</args>
				</action>
			</action>
		</action>
	</action>
</action>

<action class='meenahTalk1' sprite='latula' command='talk' name='Talk to Meenah.'><args>
      @latula_happytalk LATULA: yo yo, guppyd3 m4 grrrl !
      @meenah_idle MEENAH: merde tula
      @meenah_talk:#donnant-des-noms-comme-des-cibars-bon-marché MEENAH: j’avais oublié à quel point tu aimes jongler entre les surnoms rads que tu nous donnes 
      @meenah_fish MEENAH: tu sais j’ai toujours pense que pepetes etait plutot cool pourquoi tu ten tiendrais pas a ca
      @latula_happier:#WOO LATULA: b13n sur ! mo1 4uss1 j3 l41m3 b13n c3lu1 l4, p3p3t3s 4lors. H1GH F1V3 GRL !!!
      @meenah_angry:#OOW MEENAH: non on va pas OWWWWWW
      @latula_idle3:#>8( LATULA: ooh d3sol33, j3 t41 f41t m4l ???
      @meenah_idle MEENAH: nnn... non ? je voulais dire
      @meenah_happier:#uh#yeah MEENAH: wwwwWOWWWWWW
      @meenah_ohyes MEENAH: genre "WOWWWWW ca cetait un frappement de main radical"
      @latula_happier:#l3-plus-cool LATULA: B13N SUR QU3 C4 L3T41T !!! bord3l c3st cool qu3 tu so1s d3 r3tour.
      @meenah_idle MEENAH: cest bien tout ça mais
      @meenah_talk:#voile-de-bateau#ouais-cest-tire-par-les-cheveux-comme-jeu-de-mots#on-va-dire-que-ca-compte MEENAH: Tu ne serais pas un VOILE en train d'exagerer notre relation anterieure comme etant plus que simplement neutre ?
      @latula_annoyedtalk:#l3-gr4nd-4n34nt1ss3m3nt#4n4log13-r4d1c4l3m3nt-mort3ll3 LATULA: p3ut 3tr3 b13n. m41s j41 3u tout l3 t3mps dy p3ns3r, qu3 c4 so1t 4v4nt ou 4pr3s 4vo1r m4ng3 l3s p1ss3nl1ts p4r l4 r4c1n3.
      @latula_annoyedtalk LATULA: 3t j41 3u qu3lqu3s FOLL3S r3v3l4t1ons 4 ton propos, ou 4u notr3. j3 m3 tromp41s tot4l3m3nt sur ton compt3
      @latula_angry LATULA: dur4nt l4 m4j3ur p4rt13 du t3mps ou nous nous somm3s cotoy33s, j3t41s 3n mod3 POURQUO1 Y 4UR41T 1L D3UX F1LL3S B4D4SS “D4NS-T4-F4C3” D4NS L3 GROUP3 ???
      @latula_talk LATULA: qu3lqu3 p3u 3x4g3r3, n3st-c3 p4s ?
      @meenah_idle:#u-searious? MEENAH: mehhh
      @latula_talk LATULA: 1 w4s k1nd of v13w1ng you 4s 4 comp3t1tor, 1n l1k3 4 two grl RAD-OFF. 1 w4s w1nn1ng 1n my m1nd, of cours3. but s33, 1 h4d 1t 4ll wrong!!!!
      @meenah_idle MEENAH: did you
      @latula_happytalk LATULA: Y3AH! s33, 1m th3 t34mz R4D GRL, wh3r34s YOUR3 th3 t34mz B4D GRL!!!! 1t 4ll m4k3s p3rf3ct s3ns3! do3snt th4t m4k3 SO MUCH S3NS3???
      @meenah_annoyed MEENAH: that
      @meenah_wut2:#p-lame-tules MEENAH: is the stupidest glubbin thing to require any sorta rationalization i ever heard
      @latula_laugh LATULA: s33 p4ych3ck? 1 kn3w 1 could count on you to b3 just1f14bly cyn1c4l 4bout my n3urot1c bullsh1t. you RUL3!!!
      <!--  -->
</args></action>

<action class='meenahTalk2' sprite='porrim' command='talk' name='Talk to Meenah.'><args>
      @porrim_talk PORRIM: I really can't blame yo+u fo+r being in such a hurry to+ go+ kill him.
      @meenah_idle MEENAH: huh
      @porrim_annoyed:#Sno+tty-brat-privilege PORRIM: The Lo+rd o+f Time. Actually, it's a go+o+d example o+f what I've always been trying to+ say to+ Kankri, but he do+esn't buy it.
      @porrim_talk PORRIM: After the scratch, o+ur wo+rld co+ntinued to+ be matriarchal upo+n superficial o+bservatio+n, but was subject to+ a co+nsiderably mo+re sinister, clo+aked fo+rm o+f patriarchal tyranny all alo+ng.
      @meenah_idle MEENAH: water you talking about
      @porrim_talk:#An-excellent-ho+st PORRIM: Yo+ur po+st-scratch self, who+ grew up to+ be the empress, was really just the Lo+rd's slave all alo+ng. Implicity during her lo+ng reign, thro+ugh manipulatio+n by his cunning emplo+yee. 
      @porrim_talk PORRIM: And then explicitly, after the extinctio+n o+f o+ur race. She fo+rmally became his servant, and did his bidding lo+ng thereafter.
      @meenah_angry MEENAH: W)(AT!!!!!
      @porrim_talk:#The-o+utco+me-was-so+mewhat-different-this-time PORRIM: He did the same with Damara. She was his lo+yal Time Witch, helping him turn o+ur wo+rld into+ the nightmare it became. When her usefulness came to+ an end, he pitted yo+u and her against each o+ther, in I guess a twisted redux o+f the co+nflict yo+u and she had in the past.
      @meenah_angrytalk MEENAH: yo that is so messed up!
      @porrim_angrytalk PORRIM: The bo+tto+m line is, in additio+n to+ being an all aro+und bastard, this guy appears to+ enjo+y being especially nasty to+ girls.
      @porrim_surprisetalk PORRIM: If it's true he's hunting do+wn the gho+st o+f his departed "sister", then I really feel so+rry fo+r her.
      @meenah_angrytalk:#RARRRG)( MEENAH: NO FUCK T)(AT
      @meenah_angrytalk:#AARRRRAAAWWWRRG)(G MEENAH: I AM GOING TO SLAUG)(T-ER T)(AT UGLY MUSCL-E MONST-ER
      @meenah_angrytalk:#AAAUURGRURGGU)(G)()( MEENAH: I WILL ST-EAL )(IS S)(ITTY COAT AND W-EAR IT ON MY T)(RON-E
      @meenah_angrytalk:#ARRARARGLAAARUGRGURGGLE MEENAH: I WILL RIP OFF )(IS SKULL AND GILD IT AND T)(-EN I WILL W-EAR IT AS MY CROWN W)(IL-E )(IS BL-E-EDING GR-E-EN TORSO BOWS B-EFOR-E M-E
      @porrim_surprise:#wo+w PORRIM: Um,
      @porrim_annoyedtalk PORRIM: Best o+f luck with that.
      <!--  -->
</args></action>

<action class='meenahTalk3' sprite='kankri' command='talk' name='Talk to Meenah.'><args>
      @kankri_talk KANKRI: Wh9a, Meenah. I didn't see y9u c9me in. Y9u sh9uld have c9me say hell9.
      @meenah_idle MEENAH: oh
      @meenah_talk:#or-talk-to-or-listen-to-or-be-around-you MEENAH: yeah i didnt wanna bother you and shoutier you over there
      @kankri_talk:#s9-many KANKRI: It w9uld have 6een alright. Karkat and I were 9nly a few h9urs fr9m wrapping up 9ur first 9f what I'm presuming will 6e many, many sessi9ns t9gether.
      @kankri_talk2 KANKRI: Y9u and I have s9 much t9 discuss. I've really crystallized s9me pr96lems. Eternity has really helped me make s9me pr9gress 9n issues that matter t9 every69dy. Even gr9ups 9f pe9ple wh9 d9n't technically exist. 
      @kankri_talk4:#Herding-all-these-g9ddamn-w99l6easts#Fuckin-pain-in-the-ass KANKRI: I've had a l9t 9f time t9 think. A69ut that, and a69ut us. 9ur team, I mean, and the mistakes we've made which were pr96a6ly 6lessings in disguise. I kn9w we had 9ur differences, with y9u claiming the r9le as s9rt 9f 9ur defact9 leader, in terms 9f strategy and executi9n... literal executi9n, I supp9se. While I r9se t9 pr9minence am9ng 9ur peers as the undisputed spiritual shepherd 9f the gr9up. 
      @meenah_annoyed MEENAH: uh
      @meenah_happy:#undisputed-spiritual-shepherd?#ahahahahaha MEENAH: whatever you say
      @kankri_talk2 KANKRI: I've als9 heard y9u're recruiting mem6ers f9r a militia? An9ther 69ld endeav9r. N9t surprising, th9ugh. 6ef9re y9u em6ark, I d9 h9pe y9u'll set aside at least several sweeps t9 listen t9 s9me 9f my...
      @meenah_idle MEENAH: hey vantas
      @meenah_talk:#baited-like-worms-and-such#fishin#38) MEENAH: i really want to hear more of your garbage and lisfin to it all with hella baited breath
      @meenah_talk MEENAH: like i really really missed that you have no idea
      @meenah_talk MEENAH: but i have to go do
      @meenah_idle:#uh#yeah MEENAH: a thing
      @meenah_happy MEENAH: reel quick
      @kankri_idle KANKRI: 9h.
      @meenah_talk MEENAH: can you wait
      @meenah_talk MEENAH: like right H-ER-E
      @meenah_talk MEENAH: exactly this spot
      @meenah_idle MEENAH: for a few minutes
      @kankri_idle KANKRI: A6s9lutely!
      @kankri_talk4 KANKRI: Really, n9 hurry, I'll take the time t9 prepare s9me 9f my 9pening statements t9 6etter c9ntextualize my pr9hi6itively l9quaci9us harangue. I mean friendly 6anter.
      @meenah_creepy MEENAH: brb dog
      <!-- then "Be Meenah?" prompt -->
</args></action>

<action class='aradiaTalk1' command='talk' name='Talk.'><args>
      @aradia_happy ARADIA: greetings!
      @aradia_happytalk ARADIA: ive been meaning to say hello since you arrived
      @meenah_idle MEENAH: ...
      @meenah_angrytalk:#aw-hell-no MEENAH: M-EGIDO???
      @aradia_talk ARADIA: yes but not the one youre thinking of
      @meenah_talk MEENAH: which one then
      @aradia_talk:#you-know#the-afterlife? ARADIA: i like to consider myself as something of a caretaker for this place
      @aradia_laugh:#:D ARADIA: id refer to myself as an excellent host but that has become kind of a loaded phrase
      @meenah_talk MEENAH: you look like megido
      @meenah_annoyedtalk MEENAH: but you sure dont sound like any megido i know
      @aradia_idle ARADIA: i should hope not!
      @aradia_talk:#even-though-'time'-is-really-just-a-figure-of-speech-here ARADIA: anyway those of us who are concerned with the preservation of reality have been looking forward to this day for some time
      @meenah_wut:#the-sky-just-broke#stupid-fairy MEENAH: why would you be lookin forward to this shit
      @aradia_talk ARADIA: not the devastation so much as your arrival
      @aradia_happytalk ARADIA: you have some big plans yes?
      @meenah_annoyed:#maybe MEENAH: ...
      @meenah_annoyedtalk MEENAH: whats it to you
      @aradia_talk ARADIA: oh nothing! i am merely extending the courtesy of a formal welcome
      @aradia_talk ARADIA: now off with you! go find your friends
      @aradia_talk ARADIA: that IS why youve finally come out of your palace isnt it?
      @meenah_idle MEENAH: yeah
      @meenah_annoyedtalk:#but-i-got-my-eye-on-you#megido-lookin-fairy MEENAH: guess ill get goin then
      @aradia_happy ARADIA: ta!
      <!--  -->
</args></action>

<action class='aradiaTalk2' command='talk' name='Talk.'><args>
@aradia_idle ARADIA: lost?
      @meenah_annoyed MEENAH: i uh
      @meenah_annoyed MEENAH: went the wrong way
      @aradia_talk ARADIA: yes thats a dead end
      @aradia_talk ARADIA: where you want to go is
      @aradia_point ARADIA: THAT way
      @aradia_wink:#double-pistols#and-a-;) ARADIA: *nk-nkt*
      @meenah_annoyed MEENAH: thanks
      @meenah_annoyed MEENAH: weirdo
</args></action>

<action class='andrewTalk1' command='talk' name='Talk.'>
	<args>
			@meenah_idle MEENAH: yo orange guy
			@meenah_idle MEENAH: or uh
			@meenah_idle:#squash-colored? MEENAH: yellow guy
			@! .............
			@meenah_idle:#what-the-fuck-is-with-all-these-8-balls MEENAH: whats your deal
			@meenah_idle MEENAH: are you uh
			@meenah_idle:#awkward MEENAH: crying?
			@! SILENCE.
			@! Bring me a horse, and I am yours forever.
			<!--  -->
	</args>
</action>

<action class='andrewTalk2' command='talk' name='Talk.'>
	<args>
			@! Oh my god, you didn't.
      @!:#could-it-be? You DIDN'T......
      @! _YOU DID_
      @! YOU BROUGHT ME A HORSE!
      @! Look at this glorious, knotted up horse hitcher. This is the most amazing present I have ever received. I will cherish it forever.
      @! So uh, hey...
      @!:#Vriska-WHO????? Do you come here often?
      @meenah_wut2 MEENAH: oh my cod
      @! Well, a deal is a deal.
      @! I am now at your command.
      @meenah_wut MEENAH: why...
      @meenah_wut MEENAH: WHY did i have to bring this idiot that horse hitcher
      <!--  -->
	</args>
	<action command='removeAction'>
		<args>andrew,Talk.</args>
		<action command='follow'>
			<args>andrew,meenah</args>
			<action command='deltaSprite'>
				<args>questSwitch,20,0</args>
			</action>
		</action>
	</action>
</action>
</classes></sburb>
